YOFETAHE S. HABTU

(206) 887 6266 • <u>yofetahe@gmail.com</u> www.linkedin.com/in/yofetahe-habtu/ • https://github.com/yofetahe

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Full stack developer with 4+ years of web-based application development experience. Proactive learner, continuously improving skills and researching leading-edge tools to ensure relevant knowledge within constantly changing IT landscape. Determined to contribute value to the group or project I am working on. Work with my colleagues collaboratively to result in unified applications.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, C#, Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, XML, jQuery

Web Technology: AJAX, JSP, Socket.io, Node.js

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB

Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, Angular, React with Redux, MVC .NET, Express.js, Flask, Django, Bootstrap

Tools: Eclipse/STS, MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ, NetBeans

Cloud Platform: Pivotal Cloud Foundry, AWS

Methodology: OOP, MVC, Agile **Platforms**: Windows, Mac OS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- I. Software Engineer, June 2019 till present | HCL Technologies, WA, USA
 - Attend intensive training on front end (JavaScript, React, Angular and CSS) and Java technologies (Java and Node.js) and also Cloud Infrastructure (Cloud Foundry, Azure and AWS)
 - Develop sample project (Commercial site using React, Java and MySQL) at the end of the training and deploy the app on cloud foundry.
 - Shadow senior software engineers on the front-end features and back end functionality development using React and Java

Technology Used: Java 8, Spring, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate, JavaScript, React (with Redux & hook-context), Angular, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Jenkins, MySQL Database, IntelliJ and Eclipse/STS, Windows operating system, Cloud Foundry, Azure, AWS.

- II. Software Engineer, March 2015 to April 2018 | YamGet IT Solutions Plc Addis Ababa, ETH
 - Develop the common user authorization and authentication app for all company's applications
 - Work on the back-end and front-end development, test and maintain applications.
 - Facilitated customization of best practices to adopt emerging standards for application development architecture and tools.
 - Participated in project presentations to end users and managers to make the software solutions easy-to-understand.
 - Help on major deals via generating well formatted presentation document of the applications.
 - Research, design, develop and implement scalable applications for clients

Projects: Freight Management System, School Management System, Building Administration System, Medical Service License Management System, Document Flow Management System, Human Resource Management System

Technology Used: Spring, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Stratus 2, Hibernate, Java, JSP, JavaScript, Angular, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL Database, MySQL workbench, Eclipse/STS, Tomcat, Windows operating system.

- III. Software Engineer, April 2014 March 2015 | Apposit LLC Addis Ababa, ETH
 - Fix bugs from the existing system and develop new features as per end users request
 - Work on the back-end development of application enhancement to a new version,
 - Develop new sub project based on requirement document when a new firm join the platform.

Projects: Connect (Report Management System), PAGA (Financial System)

Technology Used: Java, JSP, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, GIT, MySQL Database, MongoDB, MySQL workbench, Grails & Spring framework, Groovy, Restful Web Service, Tomcat, Spring Tools Suite (STS), Ubuntu.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Management Information System

Micro-Link Information Technology College, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia | September 2005 – August 2009 Coursework:

Object-Oriented Programming (Java) • Windows Programming (VB) • Front End Programming (HTML, JS & CSS) • Database Management Systems • Software Project Management • Information Systems • Networking • System Analysis & Design

CERTIFICATION

CFCD: Cloud Foundry Certified Developer

By Linux Foundation Issued Dec 2019

Certificate ID Number: CFCD-1900-0579-0200

OCP: Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer

By Oracle

Issued August 2015

Certificate ID Number: 2260944270CPJSE6P

SHORT TERM CERTIFICATE PROGRAM

Full Stack Development Certificate

Coding Dojo, Bellevue USA | January – April, 2019

Coursework:

Web-Fundamental (HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, Balsamiq) • **Python Stack** (Python Core, Flask, Ajax, Django, MySQL, AWS) • **MEAN Stack** (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js, Socket.io) • **C# Stack** (C# core, ASP.NET, Entity Framework)